Guide to the R. E. Blair Collection of Western Oil and Mining Investment Prospectuses
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
R. E. Blair collection of Western oil and mining investment prospectuses
1928-1941
WA MSS S-2611
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.5
(7 boxes)
The collection consists of promotional material, including form letters, maps, reprints of newspaper articles, and publications, that describe oil and mining investment opportunities in various Western states, including Texas, Colorado, Arizona, Nevada, and New Mexico, during the time period of the Great Depression. The materials were sent to R. E. Blair as a prospective investor in oil and mining ventures.
Blair, R. E.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Sindell and Company on the Thomas W. Streeter Fund, 2008.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
R. E. Blair
R. E. Blair was a resident of Keene, New Hampshire during the late 1920s to the early 1940s.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of promotional material, including form letters, maps, reprints of newspaper articles, and publications, that describe oil and mining investment opportunities in various Western states, including Texas, Colorado, Arizona, Nevada, and New Mexico, during the time period of the Great Depression. The materials were sent to R. E. Blair as a prospective investor in oil and mining ventures.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into four series: I. Texas Oil Investments,1928-1941. II. Colorado Oil and Mining Investments, 1928-1940. III. Oil and Mining Investments in Other States and Mexico, 1928-1941. IV. Other Investment Material, 1929-1941.
Investments -- United States; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado; Mines and mineral resources -- Nevada; Petroleum -- Colorado; Petroleum -- Louisiana; Petroleum -- New Mexico; Petroleum -- Texas; Form letters; Promotional materials; Prospectuses; Blair, R. E.
- Texas Oil Investments, 1928-1941; Series I; 1.47 linear feet (4 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by business name.
  Scope and Contents
  Series consists of prospectus material for oil investment opportunities in Texas or with Texas-based companies. Specific geographical areas in Texas include Blanco County, Callahan County, Cooke County, Howard County, Jones County, LaSalle County, Mills County, Pecos County, and Shackelford County, among others. Also found is some prospectus material for other types of investments, such as the Bayou Chane salt dome.
  - A. H. Bowers, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albert Spencer, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andy Lacy Oil Royalties, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arthur H. Wray, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - B. J. (Joe) Hall, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Banner & Elmore, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bayou-Chane Salt Dome, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ben Banner, 1931-1935 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Biltmore Oil Company, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bob Elmore, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bob McCann, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bunker & Company, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - C. A. Bonds & Company, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - C. C. Massey, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - C. J. Mellen, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - C. M. Joiner, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - C. M. Williams, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clyde D. Lane, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Consolidated Grain & Cotton Company, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Daniel C. Regan, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - E. B. Tinsley, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - E. R. Cosby, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - E. W. Jarman & Company, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Earl P. Corley, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ekman Investment Company, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Frank P. Fildes & Company, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Forest Oil Corporation, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Frank E. Haynes, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - General Minerals Company, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Geo. H. Campbell, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gibralter Trust & Finance Company, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Greene Oil & Refining Company, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Guillot Company, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - H. J. McMullen, 1928-1930 (Box 2, Folder 35-37)
  - H. H. Hoffman, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Harry W. Elliott, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Howard M. Jones, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Investment Forecast, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - J. F. Morrissey Company, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - J. H. McKenzie, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - J. L. Tomberlin, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - J. M (Joe) Burnham, 1929-1936 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - James L. Nelson (Nelson Holding Company), 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
  - Joe Hoover, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - John W. Westbrook Company, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Kennedy Rogers, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Kenneth E. Liebhart, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Lincoln D. Steele, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Lloyd Oil Corporation, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Logan Fain, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - M. N. Shoemaker, 1927-1929 (Box 3, Folder 55-57)
  - Manning & Company, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Midfield Royalties Inc., 1931 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Mid-Tex Company, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Oil & Market Barometer, 1933-1935 (Box 3, Folder 61-63)
  - Original Developers Pool, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - The Permian Company, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Priest & Company, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - R. D. Kercheval, 1928-1929 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - R. E. Moore, Inc., 1929 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - R. Franklin Smith, 1929-1936 (Box 3, Folder 69-70)
  - R. G. Baker, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - R. L. Crawford, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Ralph R. Malone, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Rio Neches, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Steele & Company, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Sun Royalty Company, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - T. G. Shaw, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Terry Morgan, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Texas Petroleum Company, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Texas Royalty Company, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Trans-Pecos Royalties, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - W. A. Greves, 1929-1930 (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - W. A. Patterson, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - W. A. Robinson, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - W. D. "Andy" Anderson, 1929 (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Western Royalty Exchange, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Wales & Company, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - War. Wood Hunt, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - World Oil Company, 1928-1929 (Box 4, Folder 89)
- Colorado Oil and Mining Investments, 1928-1940; Series II; 0.63 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Arranged into two subseries: Oil Investments and Mining Investments. Material within subseries arranged alpabetically by business name.
  Series consists of prospectus material for oil and mining investment opportunities in Colorado or with Colorado-based companies.
  - Oil Investments
    - Frank Job, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - Macon & Company, Inc., 1937, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - R. M. "Dick" Barnholt, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Rocky Mountain Company, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - Walter Knox & Company, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 94-95)
  - Mining Investments
    - B. E. Simpson & Company, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 96)
    - Carroll & Company, Inc., 1932-1940 (Box 6, Folder 97-98)
    - Chas. S. Downing, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 99)
    - Cripple Creek Development Corporation, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 100)
    - David Garrett & Company, undated (Box 6, Folder 101)
    - Donald A. McCallum, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 102)
    - Downs & Company, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 103)
    - Fred W. Miller & Company, 1935-1937 (Box 6, Folder 104)
    - Foreman & Company, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 105)
    - Gleason & Company, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 106)
    - Gold Hub Mines Company, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 107)
    - Golden Gilpin Ore Reduction & Refining Company, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 108)
    - J. N. Caldwell, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 109)
    - James J. Spillane & Company, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 110)
    - John C. Martelon, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 111)
    - Kamp & Company, 1929-1937 (Box 6, Folder 112-113)
    - Kenneth C. Wilson, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 114)
    - Marrin Bell & Company, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - McDowell Mines, Inc., 1937 (Box 6, Folder 116)
    - Mytus Gold Corporation, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 117)
    - R. E. Young & Company, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 118)
    - P. B. Rosebrough & Company, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 119)
    - Stern-Stovall Corporation, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 120)
    - United Empires Gold Mining Corporation, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 121)
    - Ute Gold Mining Company, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Valley Production Company, Inc., 1939 (Box 6, Folder 123)
    - Western States Mining Company, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 124)
    - Wm. F. Ryan, 1936-1937 (Box 6, Folder 125)
- Oil and Mining Investments in Other States and Mexico, 1928-1941; Series III; 0.3 linear feet (14 folders)
  Arranged alphabetically by state, and then alphabetically by business name.
  Series consists of prospectus material for oil and mining investment opportunities in various states and in Mexico.
  - Arkansas
    - American Diamond Corporation, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 126)
    - Merchants & Farmers Bank, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 127)
  - Arizona
    - Comstock-Dexter Mines, Inc., 1935 (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Indiana
    - Roy S. Cameron, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Louisiana
    - Hubert Dickey, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 130)
    - Humphreys Oil Corporation, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Mexico
    - Jno. Cabot McDonald & Company, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Nevada
    - Pryce & Company, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Western Ore Milling Company, 1935-1936 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - New Mexico
    - Tract Headquarters, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Oklahoma
    - Big Indian Royalty Pool, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Carrol Holiday, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - James K. McKenzie, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - National Bond & Mortage Company, Inc., 1930 (Box 7, Folder 139)
- Other Investment Material, 1929-1941; Series IV; 0.1 linear feet (4 folders)
  Series consists of various financial and investment-related publications and subscription offers.
  - The Oil News, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 140-141)
  - Oil and Mining Publications, 1929-1941 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Subscription Offers, 1932, undated (Box 7, Folder 143)